The creative process -- you know this --
众所周知，创意过程
from the first idea to the final product,
从第一个想法冒出来到最终产品
is a long process.
是一个很长的过程。
It's super-iterative, lots of refinement,
需要超级多的 反复迭代，无数的改进，
blood, sweat, tears and years.
血汗，泪水和时间。
And we're not saying you're going to go out for a walk
我们讨论的并不是，你出去散个步，
and come back with the Sistine Chapel in your left hand.
左手就可以带着 西斯廷教堂（的设计）回来。
So what frame of the creative process did we focus on?
那么我们关注的是 创意过程的哪个环节？
Just this first part.
就是这第一部分。
Just brainstorming, coming up with a new idea.
去做头脑风暴，产生新点子。
We actually ran four studies with a variety of people.
我们针对一些不同的人做过四项研究，
You were either walking indoors or outdoors.
包括了进行户外和室内散步的群体。
And all of these studies found the same conclusion.
所有的这些研究都得出了相同的结论。
I'm only going to tell you about one of them today.
我今天只打算告诉你们其中一个例子。
One of the tests we used for creativity was alternate uses.
我们做创意研究的其中 一个测试是替代使用。
In this test, you have four minutes.
在这个测试中，你有4分钟的时间
Your job is to come up with as many other ways to use common everyday objects
要想出尽可能多的方法 去使用生活中你所能想到的
as you can think of.
日常事物。
So, for example, what else would you do with a key,
比如，除了开门外，
other than to use it for opening up a lock?
你还能用钥匙做什么？
Clearly, you could use it as a third eyeball for a giraffe, right?
显然，你还可以它来当作长颈鹿的 第三只眼睛，没错吧？
Maybe. That's sort of interesting, kind of new. But is it creative?
或许如此。但诸如此类好玩的 新使用方法，算是创意吗？
So people came up with as many ideas as they could,
虽然人们想出了各种各样的主意，
and we had to decide:
而我们需要判断，
Is this creative or not?
这是不是创意？
The definition of creativity that a lot of people go with
很多人对创意的定义是
is "appropriate novelty."
“适用的新奇”。
For something to be appropriate, it has to be realistic,
要让事情变得适用，就需要实用。
so unfortunately, you can't use a key as an eyeball.
但不幸的是， 你无法将钥匙当眼球使用。
Boo!
这不算数。
But "novel," the second thing, is that nobody had to have said it.
而第二点，新奇， 是指之前没有人提到过。
So for us, it had to be appropriate first,
所以对我们而言，这首先得适用，
and then for novelty,
然后是新奇，
nobody else in the entire population that we surveyed could have said it.
已知的地球人都没有想到这个。
So you might think you could use a key to scratch somebody's car,
所以如果你说可以 用钥匙来刮花别人的车，
but if somebody else said that, you didn't get credit for it.
但如果已经有人说过了， 就不够新奇了。
Neither of you did.
你们都不算。
However, only one person said this:
然而，只有其中一个人这样说:
"If you were dying and it were a murder mystery,
“假如你快要死去，而且是被谋杀的，
and you had to carve the name of the murderer into the ground
你就可以（用钥匙） 把遗嘱和凶手的名字一起
with your dying words."
刻在地上。”
One person said this.
有个人就是这样说。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
And it's a creative idea, because it's appropriate and it's novel.
所以这是一个创造性的想法， 因为适用，而且新奇。
You either did this test and came up with ideas while you were seated
你参与这个测试的 时候是可以是坐着的，
or while you were walking on a treadmill.
也可以是在跑步机上走步。
(Laughter)
（笑声）
They did the test twice, with different objects.
他们做了这个测试两次， 每次都针对不同的人群。
Three groups: the first group sat first
三个组，第一组第一次坐着回答，
and then sat again for the second test.
第二次测试也是坐着回答。
The second group sat first
第二组，第一次先坐着，
and then did the second test while walking on a treadmill.
第二次则在跑步机上走着。
The third group -- and this is interesting --
第三组，就比较有意思了，
they walked on the treadmill first, and then they sat.
他们第一次先在跑步机上走， 然后再坐下回答问题。
OK, so the two groups that sat together for the first test,
那么两个先坐着测试的小组，
they looked pretty similar to each other,
他们的想法彼此差异不大，
and they averaged about 20 creative ideas per person.
每个人平均有20个创意。
The group that was walking on the treadmill
那个在跑步机上行走的小组
did almost twice as well.
几乎想出了两倍的创意。
And they were just walking on a treadmill in a windowless room.
而他们做的无非是在没有窗户的室内， 在跑步机上散步了一会儿。
Remember, they took the test twice.
记住，他们每组人测试了两次。
The people who sat twice for that second test didn't get any better;
两次都坐着的受试者， 第二次的成绩并没有变好，
practice didn't help.
练习并无帮助。
But these same people who were sitting and then went on the treadmill
但先坐着，然后在跑步机上行走的人，
got a boost from walking.
成绩出现了飙升。
Here's the interesting thing.
这就是有趣的地方。
The people who were walking on the treadmill
在跑步机上行走的人
still had a residue effect of the walking,
表现出了散步的残余效应，
and they were still creative afterwards.
后期仍然富有创意。
So the implication of this is that you should go for a walk
这个研究的启发就是， 在你的一个重要会议开始前，
before your next big meeting and just start brainstorming right away.
你应该出去散个步， 然后立马开始头脑风暴。
We have five tips for you
我们有5点提示，
that will help make this the best effect possible.
将会帮你取得最好的效果。
First, you want to pick a problem or a topic to brainstorm.
首先，你需要带着要进行 头脑风暴的问题或话题。
So, this is not the shower effect,
这并不是冲凉效应，
when you're in the shower and all of a sudden,
你洗着澡，突然之间，
a new idea pops out of the shampoo bottle.
新的主意就从满头的 泡沫中冒出来了。
This is something you're thinking about ahead of time.
而是你提前就在思考的东西。
They're intentionally thinking about brainstorming a different perspective
在行走的时候下意识的 用不同的视角
on the walk.
进行头脑风暴。
Secondly -- I get asked this a lot:
第二——我常常被人问，
Is this OK while running?
跑步的时候也行吗？
Well, the answer for me is that if I were running,
好吧，对我来讲，我跑步的时候
the only new idea I would have would be to stop running, so ...
唯一想到的新主意就是停下来······
(Laughter)
（笑声）
But if running for you is a comfortable pace, good.
但假如跑步对你 是一种非常舒适的运动，那没问题。
It turns out, whatever physical activity is not taking a lot of attention.
不论是哪种体力活动， 只要不分担太多注意力就行。
So just walking at a comfortable pace is a good choice.
所以在舒适的地方散步 是蛮好的选择。
Also, you want to come up with as many ideas as you can.
另外，去想出尽可能多的主意。
One key of creativity is to not lock on that first idea.
创意的一个关键是 不要纠结在第一个主意上。
Keep going.
继续前进。
Keep coming up with new ones, until you pick one or two to pursue.
继续想新的主意， 直至你选择出1-2个来深入思考。
You might worry that you don't want to write them down,
你可能会担心如果不把它写下来
because what if you forget them?
回头忘记了怎么办？
So the idea here is to speak them.
最好的方法是把它说出来。
Everybody was speaking their new ideas.
每个人都说出他们的新主意。
So you can put your headphones on and record through your phone
你可以带上耳机，用手机录下来，
and then just pretend you're having a creative conversation, right?
就假想自己在进行一场 有创意的对话，没错吧？
Because the act of writing your idea down is already a filter.
因为把主意写下来的动作 就是一种过滤。
You're going to be like, "Is this good enough to write down?"
你不由得会想： “这真的值得写下来吗？”
And then you write it down.
然后才会动笔。
So just speak as many as you can, record them and think about them later.
所以尽可能多的去说出来，录下来， 事后再花时间认真思考。
And finally: don't do this forever. Right?
最后，不要一直这么做。
If you're on the walk and that idea's not coming to you,
如果散步并不能给你带来好主意，
come back to it later at another time.
稍后再来一次。
I think we're coming up on a break right now,
我想现在我们就需要稍作休息了，
so I have an idea:
我有个主意：
Why don't you grab a leash
何不带上你的宠物，
and take your thoughts for a walk?
带着你的想法出去溜达一圈？
Thank you.
谢谢。
(Applause)
（鼓掌）